# 大家好 現在都下霜啦 村里面荷包豆啊
Hi everyone! It's frosty these days. The poached beans in our village,
# 全部都 被打死了
are all dead.
# 就只剩下那個根了
And now only the roots remain.
# 你看
Look!
# 好多啊
A lot!
# 我去搞點那個
I''m going to get some, you know,
# 荷包豆蟲來吃一下
some poached bean worms as snacks.
# 剛好可以鑽進去
Then, I can squeeze in.
# 你看 這裡有一個
Look! Here's one.
# 就是這種蟲子
It's exactly this kind of bugs.
# 還小的候這樣 還小的很好吃的哦
And this is the small one. The small ones are really tasty.
# 現在長大了就這樣
When it grows up, it becomes like this one.
# 長大成這樣子就不了口了
There's no way to eat it when it has grown up.
# 這個蟲子
This bug
# 還小的時候我們經常抓這個玩
As kids, we used to play with these bugs.
# 好冷啊 它
It's very cold.
# 你看 這樣就兩根 我再去其它地方找一下
Look! Here are just two. Let me see if I can find any more at other places.
# 你看 這個
Look! This one is,
# 那麼大的
so large.
# 砍斷
Chop it off!
# 這兄弟不要了的
My buddy doesn't want it anymore.
# 這個肯定
There must be,
# 有幾十個啊
a few dozens here.
# 這後面也有
There are some more behind me.
# 這裡
Here
# 寧可殺錯全部 也不要放過一個
Killing all innocents, is better than missing one.
# 可能就一個
Perhaps there's just one.
# 可能哦
I say perhaps.
# 不知道有還是沒有
I don't know if there are really any.
# 這個也有
This one too
# 哎喲
Ayo!
# 掉了一個草進肚子
A leaf drops into my belly.
# 沒有白來
At least not leaving empty-handed.
# 雖然就一點點 繼續找一下
Though it's just a bit. Let me try to find more.
# 這兩根肯有的 這兩根
There must be some in these two, these two.
# 就搞了那麼一點點
So we have just a tiny little bit here.
# 我回去要它剝一下 看一下它有多少
Let me get back and crack them all, and see how many we have.
# 這裡
Here,
# 這裡有幾個
here are some.
# 你看 這裡有一個
Look! Here's one,
# 兩個
two,
# 三個
three
# 今年這個蟲子好少啊
There are only a few this kind of worms this year.
# 搞那麼多才搞了那麼一丟丟
We have here just a tiny little bit from so many branches.
# 再打架啊
You dare to fight again?
# 搞個牙簽肉
Let's make skewers.
# 那麼多藤子就搞了那麼一點點
Here are the tiny little bit from so many branches.
# 都不夠吃啊
It just can't be enough.
# 等下我去搞點兄弟家的玉米來
Let me get some corns from my buddy in a while.
# 我去拿一個竹簽把它們通通串起來
Let me fetch some bamboo sticks and pierce them all onto the sticks.
# 先放在這裡先
Let me first, put it here first.
# 好 把它串起來
Alright! Put them onto the sticks.
# 你看 把它串起來啦
Look! They're all on the sticks now.
# 等下我用那個鹽先撒一下
I'll sprinkle some salt.
# 不然沒鹽不好吃的
It won't taste good without salt.
# 搞去鹽來
Let me fetch some salt.
# 撒點鹽
Put some salt.
# 這樣就有鹽啦
So now they're salted,
# 就可以直接開烤
and can be grilled right away.
# 哇 它們還在動
Wa! They're still moving.
# 沒事 很快的 啊 這個火很
No worries. It won't take long. Ah! The fire is really,
# 這個火
the fire,
# 很燙的哦
is really hot, you know.
# 一下就不 不會動啦
You'll stop, stop moving in a second.
# 忍一忍啊
Hang in there!
# 哇 好香啊
Wa! It smells so good!
# 你看 這個蟲子它會跳舞的哦
Look! The worms are dancing.
# 妖艷的姿勢
So seducing!
# 你看 這蟲子在火裡面滾來滾去的
Look! The worms are rolling around in the fire.
# 受熱就比較均勻
So they can be heated more evenly.
# 均勻
Evenly
# 火力均勻的話就比較好吃
It tastes much better when they're evenly heated.
# 犧牲了你們小小的生命
Your tiny little lives are sacrificed,
# 給我們供給 供給我們那麼多營養
to provide us, to provide us with so much nutrition.
# 這些蟲子都好偉大啊
The worms are really great creatures.
# 這個蛋白質很高的哦
The worms are very rich in protein,
# 富含微量元素
minerals and vitamins.
# 特別好吃
Really tasty.
# 那 那麼多狗 走開點啊
So, so many dogs.Go 'way!
# 等下我吃完了給你 給你那個
Let me finish first. Then I'll give you, give you the,
# 這個竹簽子給你們舔兩一就好啦
the sticks, which you can lick, and that's it.
# 你幹嘛
What are you doing?
# 是不是很想吃是不是
You really wanna have some, don't you?
# 想吃你就說啊
Say it if you really want some.
# 說出來我就給你吃啊
Say it and then it's yours.
# 你們又不說
But you don't say anything.
# 我怎麼知道你想甚麼
Then how can I know what you're thinking about?
# 加點孜然粉
Put some cumin powder.
# 這個手 這個手比較笨
This hand, this hand is not so agile.
# 這個右手才行
I need to use my right hand.
# 撒在你的傷口上
Rub it into your wounds.
# 太浪費啦
I'm wasting too much.
# 再烤十秒鐘就可以吃啦
It's done in ten seconds.
# 四秒鐘
Four second.
# 可以啦
It's alright now.
# 啊 先嘗一下
Ah! Let me try and see,
# 好不好吃先
if it tastes good.
# 哎呀 剛剛吃了一個沒熟
Aya! That one was still not ready.
# 搞了一嘴都是那個汁
The fluid blasted in my mouth.
# 受不了
Yuck!
# 烤熟點行了
I need to grill a bit longer.
# 可能我太猴急了
Perhaps I was too impatient.
# 你看 現在烤好啦
Look! It's really done now.
# 先嘗一下
Let me try.
# 嗯
Um!
# 好香啊
It smells so good!
# 外焦裡嫩
Crispy skin, tender meat.
# 你們不能吃的 知不知道
You guys can't eat. Do you get it?
# 這東西不好吃的
These things taste extremely bad.
# 你們吃了會拉肚子
They will upset your stomach.
# 走開
Go 'way!
# 等一下晚上給你伴米糠伴飯啊
You'll have rice with bran in the evening.
# 來 給老弟他們吃
C'mon! Let's give it to our younger brothers.
# 嘗一下哥的手藝
See how well I make it.
# 好吃
Wonderful!
# 那麼假的嗎
What a hypocrite!
# 我不敢吃
I dare not!
# 胡跃金
Hu Yuejin!
# 我也不敢吃
I dare not neither!
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 準備煮飯餵竹鼠
I'm gonna cook for the bamboo rats.